khanacademy.org 2016-06-15

# Privacy Notice | Khan Academy

#### Last Updated: May 10, 2016

_Our mission at Khan Academy is to provide a free, world-class education for anyone, anywhere._

Khan Academy is a proud supporter of the Student Privacy Pledge to safeguard student privacy. 

* * *

###  Our Privacy Notice is fueled by our commitment to the following Privacy Principles: 

  1. We’re deeply committed to creating a safe and secure online environment for you. 
  2. We do not sell your personal information to third parties. We established ourselves as a not-for-profit organization so that our mission of education and your trust will not be in conflict with a for-profit motive. 
  3. We strive to provide you with access to and control over the information you give us, and we take the protection of your information very seriously. 
  4. We take extra precautions for our younger learners under the age of 13, including restricting child accounts to automatically block features that would allow a child to post or disclose personal information. 
  5. We do not advertise on Khan Academy. We use your information to provide you with a better learning experience, not to sell you products. 

* * *

##  About Khan Academy and our Privacy Notice 

Khan Academy, Inc. (“Khan Academy”, “us”, or “we”) feels strongly about protecting your privacy. We understand how important privacy is to you, and we are committed to creating a safe and secure environment for learners of all ages. This Privacy Notice applies to khanacademy.org, our mobile application, our application programming interface (“API”), and online services (collectively, our “Properties”), which are all owned and operated by Khan Academy. This Privacy Notice describes how Khan Academy collects and uses the information you provide on our Properties, and describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information. 

As a not-for-profit, 501(c)(3) organization, we use the data we collect to provide you with a better experience and fulfill our mission of providing a free, world-class education for anyone, anywhere. We established ourselves as a not-for-profit organization so that a for-profit motive will not interfere with our mission of providing a trusted educational resource. 

Our Privacy Notice describes what information we gather from our members and others who visit and use our Properties, how we use that information, and what we do to protect it. By visiting or using our Properties, you consent to the information handling practices described in this Privacy Notice. 

Your use of our Properties and any information you provide on our Properties are subject to the terms of this Privacy Notice, which is incorporated into and subject to our Terms of Service. Any capitalized terms used but not defined within this Privacy Notice have the meaning given to them in our Terms of Service. 

* * *

##  How we collect and use data 

We take the information you provide to us very seriously, and we strive to put you in control of decisions around your information. 

#### Khan Academy collects the following information about you and your use of our Properties:

#####  Personal Information. 

When you register for, browse and use our Properties, you may provide to Khan Academy what is generally called “personally identifiable information” or “personal data” (such as your full name, email address, or a photograph of yourself) that can be used to identify you. At Khan Academy, we call this data “Personal Information”. 

#####  Information from Integrated Services like Facebook or Google. 

If you decide to register through or otherwise grant access to a third-party social networking or integrated service (what we call an “Integrated Service”), such as Facebook Connect or Google, Khan Academy may also collect Personal Information that is already associated with your Integrated Service account. You may also have the option of sharing additional information with Khan Academy through an Integrated Service. If you choose to provide such information, during registration or otherwise, you are giving Khan Academy the permission to use, share, and store it in a manner consistent with this Privacy Notice. 

#####  Information about your use of our Properties and other User-provided Information. 

We may collect usage information about your use of certain features on our Properties, such as the number of problems you have attempted, the number of videos you have viewed, and the amount of time spent to complete a problem. This enables us to better tailor educational experiences that are most appropriate for you. 

#####  Information obtained from other Users. 

We make available certain features on our Properties that allow other Users to provide us information about you. This information may include Personal Information. Generally, this occurs when parents or teachers provide information relating to a Child User. For example, a parent may register an account for their child and provide us with certain information, such as the Child’s User name and birthday. 

#####  Location Information. 

We may collect and use information about your location (such as your country) to provide you with tailored educational experiences for your region, but we don’t collect the precise geolocation of you or your device. You may be able to change the settings on your computer or mobile device to prevent it from providing us with any location information. 

#####  Information from Other Sources. 

In certain situations, we may obtain information, including Personal Information, from third parties or sources other than our Properties. For example, if you donate to Khan Academy via PayPal, we may obtain your name and mailing address to send a thank you note, or if you apply for a job with Khan Academy via an online recruiting site, we will obtain the information you provide in your application for that purpose. If we combine or associate information from other sources with Personal Information that we collect through our Properties, we will treat the combined information as Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Notice. 

####  Khan Academy uses this information in the following ways: 

#####  To enhance our Properties and the services we provide. 

Khan Academy uses the information you provide or that we collect to enhance our relationship with you and to operate, maintain, enhance, and provide all of the features and services found on our Properties. Khan Academy, for instance, remembers your recent activity so we can recommend the most appropriate content for you on your next visit. If you have given Khan Academy consent, we may use your Personal Information to provide you with information about Khan Academy’s features, services and other offerings that may be of interest to you. Under certain circumstances and if we obtain your consent (for example, if you submit a testimonial and agree to make it public), we may post your Personal Information on our Properties. 

#####  To understand how you and other Users use our Properties. 

Khan Academy uses all of the information that you provide or that we collect from Users to understand and analyze the usage trends, learning behaviors, and preferences of our Users, to improve the way the Properties work and look, and to create new features and functionality. For more information, please see the “Technologies” section, below. 

#####  To enable your participation in Khan Academy partnership arrangements. 

Khan Academy will not share Personal Information with other third-party organizations for their marketing or promotional use without your consent or except as part of a specific program or feature for which you will have the ability to opt-in. You can grant us permission to share your Personal Information with authorized partners, not-for-profit organizations, and other entities that are not affiliated with Khan Academy. In these cases, we will only provide to these third parties the information you have authorized or asked us to share to these third parties. 

If you participate in special programs, Khan Academy may collect personal information from you to facilitate those programs. For example, LearnStorm participants may be asked to provide information related to event logistics and prize awarding and processing (e.g., contact information, dietary restrictions, shirt sizes, etc.), and College Board program participants may provide information regarding study habits and test scores (e.g., the number of hours studied, modules or tests taken, scores earned, etc.). This information may be shared with our program partners for research or evaluation purposes or as otherwise permitted under this Privacy Notice. 

Khan Academy may send information or offers to you on behalf of these third parties. For example, if we partner with a not-for-profit organization running a contest in your region and send you an email notifying you of the partnership, we will only share your information with the third party if you opt-in to participate in the contest, and if so, the information we would share would be limited to that needed to facilitate your participation in the contest and enable you to redeem your prize. 

* * *

#####  Data Retention. 

Unless we receive a deletion request, we will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as is reasonably useful for operational purposes. 

#####  Technical Information. 

To provide a personalized learning and high-quality experience for our Users, we may use various technologies that automatically record certain technical information from your browser or device, including standard log files, web beacons, or pixel tags. This technical information may include your Internet Protocol (IP) address, device or browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring or exit pages, clickstream data, operating system, and the dates and times that you visit the Website. We do this to better understand how our Users are using our Website so we can improve site functionality and the services we offer you. 

Like most websites, whether or not you are a registered member, we may send one or more cookies – small text files containing a string of alphanumeric characters – to your computer. Cookies remember information about your activities on a website and enable us to provide you with a more personalized learning experience. Khan Academy may use both session cookies and persistent cookies. A session cookie disappears automatically after you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains after you close your browser and may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the Website. You can, however, remove a persistent cookie at any time. Please review your web browser “Help” file to learn the proper way to modify your cookie settings. However, without cookies you will not have access to certain services and features on the Website. 

Khan Academy uses a variety of third-party service providers, such as YouTube to host our videos or Google Analytics to understand our Website usage. We may allow third-party service providers to place and read their own cookies, web beacons, and similar technologies to collect information through the Website. This information is collected directly and automatically by these third parties, and Khan Academy does not participate in these data transmissions. Khan Academy will, wherever feasible, contractually obligate our third-party service providers to abide by the terms of this Privacy Notice. 

Khan Academy also uses Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as HTML5 to store content information and preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site may use LSOs such as HTML5 to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs. Please consult your browser’s “Help” function to learn more. 

##  How we share or transfer data 

Khan Academy takes great care to protect the information you provide us. We do not rent or sell Personal Information that we collect from Users with third parties. We also take great measures to restrict any collection or disclosure of Personal Information from children less than 13 years of age. 

####  Khan Academy will disclose User information only as described below: 

#####  If you want information shared with other Users, we’ll share it for you. 

We provide certain features that may allow you to share information with other Users. For example, you may choose to populate your profile with your name, short biography, and location. Or you may ask questions that are visible to other Users of Khan Academy. Whenever you share information with other Users of our Properties, any Personal Information that you choose to include in, or is associated with, such User Postings will be accessible by such Users. As with most online services, once you make your Personal Information available to others in any of these ways, it may be collected and used by the recipients without restriction. 

#####  We may share data with social networks at your request. 

Some of our Users choose to connect their Khan Academy account with social networks. This functionality is entirely optional. If you have explicitly agreed that we may do so, Khan Academy may disclose your Personal Information through a social network or similar service (like Facebook or Google). To control the information that you share, you have the option of modifying your Khan Academy or social network settings or disconnecting your social network account from your Khan Academy account. 

#####  We may share data with third-party applications that you authorize. 

Third-party application developers and service providers (commonly known as “App Developers“) may build complementary services for our platform, such as a mobile application for visually-impaired learners to access our resources. You may request we share your information with App Developers by connecting to the application or service and approving access to your Khan Academy account. Khan Academy has taken steps to try to ensure the safety of information accessed by App Developers and requires App Developers to comply with our API Terms of Service and this Privacy Notice. 

#####  We may share data in connection with special programs you participate in. 

If you participate in special programs where Khan Academy partners with third parties, Khan Academy may share data collected from or about you with its third party partners to facilitate the program or services being offered. For instance, if you participate in Khan Academy’s program with College Board, Khan Academy may share information regarding your study habits, tests taken, and test scores with College Board. 

#####  We may share anonymous or aggregate data to improve our services and learn more about our Users. 

In certain occasions, Khan Academy may work with business partners to improve our services or offerings. We may disclose automatically collected and other aggregate non-Personal Information to authorized business partners to conduct research on online education or assist in understanding the usage, viewing, and demographic patterns for certain programs, content, services, promotions, and/or functionality on our Properties. 

#####  We will share data when required by law. 

Khan Academy may also disclose User information if required to do so by law, or if we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with local, state, federal, international, or other applicable laws (such as U.S. Copyright law) or respond to a court order, judicial or other government subpoena, or warrant, or administrative request. In some cases, we may make such disclosures without first providing notice to Users. 

#####  We may share data in the context of a change of business, including a merger or acquisition. 

In the event that Khan Academy is acquired by or merged with a third-party entity, we may transfer or assign the information that we have collected from Users as part of such merger, acquisition, sale, or other change of control. 

#####  We may share data when necessary or appropriate to protect Khan Academy or others. 

Khan Academy may disclose information that we believe, in good faith, is appropriate or necessary to take precautions against liability; to protect Khan Academy from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful uses; to investigate and defend ourselves against any third-party claims or allegations; to assist government enforcement agencies; to protect the security or integrity of our Properties; or to protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Khan Academy, our Users, or others. 

#####  Limitations on Access to your Personal Information by Employees and Authorized Parties. 

Khan Academy’s employees, agents and contractors must have a legitimate business reason to access Personal Information you provide to Khan Academy. We may share your Personal Information with third-party service providers, including outside contractors or agents who help us manage our information activities, but they may only use your Personal Information to provide us with a specific service and not for any other purpose. Where feasible, Khan Academy will require our third-party service providers to comply with this Privacy Notice. 

* * *

##  Your choice and options in our data collection, use, and transfer 

#####  You can choose to not provide us with Personal Information. 

You may always decline to share your Personal Information with Khan Academy. Registration is not required to access most of our course content and curriculum. If you decline to register, however, Khan Academy will not be able to provide to you certain features and functionalities found on our Properties. You may later enable or access those features by providing Khan Academy with the necessary Personal Information. 

#####  You can edit or delete Personal Information in our records. 

We want you to have access to your information, so that you can help keep it as accurate as possible., If you register and provide Khan Academy with Personal Information, you may update, correct, or delete your account and information at any time by reviewing your profile information and preferences on your account settings page. Parents can modify or delete Child User accounts. If you experience any difficulties in this process, please contact us as described below. 

#####  You can disconnect us from Integrated Services. 

You may revoke Khan Academy’s access to your account on any Integrated Service, such as Google or Facebook, at any time by updating the appropriate settings in the account preferences of the respective Integrated Service. You should check your privacy settings on each Integrated Service to understand and change the information sent to us through each Integrated Service. Please review each Integrated Service’s terms of use and privacy policies carefully before using their services and connecting to our Properties. 

* * *

##  Child Users 

#####  Khan Academy is committed to children’s privacy. 

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important to Khan Academy. For that reason, we created certain features designed to help protect Personal Information relating to children who are less than 13 years of age (“Child Users”). Khan Academy does not knowingly permit Child Users to register directly for our Properties. If Khan Academy learns that Personal Information of a Child user has been collected on our Properties without parental consent, then Khan Academy will take appropriate steps to delete this information. If you are a parent or guardian (“Parent”) and discover that your child under the age of 13 has a registered account with our Properties without your consent, please alert Khan Academy at [privacy@khanacademy.org](mailto:privacy@khanacademy.org) and request that we delete that child’s personal information from our systems. 

#####  How children may register for and use our Properties. 

Child Users cannot register for a Khan Academy account themselves. If a Child User attempts to register for our Properties, Khan Academy will request the email address of that Child User’s Parent in order to seek consent from that Parent. No information about Child Users is retained during their registration attempt, except the Parent email address for purposes of seeking consent. 

If you are a Parent, you may provide consent for your child’s registration by first registering yourself on our Properties. Once registered, you can create a restricted account for your Child User, monitor the data on your Child User’s account, or revoke a child’s permission to use the Properties by deleting the account. 

Alternatively, your child can be registered to use the Properties through his or her school, or through an integration with the Properties that is supported by the child’s school, or by teachers, tutors and other similar adults who assist in the educational process (“Coaches”) who have taken steps to obtain parental consent. Parents always have the option to delete their Child User’s account. 

#####  Restrictions on Child Users. 

Khan Academy attempts to restrict a Child User’s access to certain features that could result in disclosure of Personal Information by the Child User. A restricted account limits sharing and displaying private information about the Child User in various ways, including: 

  * Restricted accounts do not include the Child User’s real name or biography section; only the Child User’s username is displayed 
  * The Parent can edit Personal Information found in the restricted account 
  * The Parent can restrict Child Users from adding Coaches 
  * The profile is not shared publicly, and only the Parent and other permitted Coaches can see the user’s profile 
  * The Child User cannot post to public discussion forums 

Some other features of our Properties may, however, permit a Child User to enter free-form text through which the Child User could enter Personal Information that would be visible to other Users. This may occur, for instance, if a Child User enters Personal Information in answering an exercise problem or creating other projects on our Properties. If you are the Parent of a Child User, please advise your Child User of the risks of posting Personal information on our Properties or any other online services, as information posted may be used by others without restriction. 

As a Parent, you can choose to share information about your child as you deem appropriate. Khan Academy won’t share Personal Information about your child or his/her progress with anyone other than you, your child and any permitted Coaches, unless we receive your permission (or as otherwise noted in this Privacy Notice). 

As a Parent, you have the ability to control information about your Child User. To review, update, or delete information collected from your Child User, you can do so in the “Your Children” section within your account. To refuse future collection or use of your child’s Personal Information, you can delete your Child User’s account or contact us at [privacy@khanacademy.org](mailto:privacy@khanacademy.org). To find out more about how Khan Academy protects Child Users, please click [here](https://www.khanacademy.org/educator/parents-and-tutors/student-privacy-for-parent/a/how-does-khan-academy-protect-students-under-age-13). 

#####  California Children’s Privacy Rights 

If you are under the age of 18, or the parent of a User under the age of 18, residing in California, you are entitled to request removal of content or information you have posted on our Properties. If you would like to request removal of your or your child’s content or information, please email us at privacy@khanacademy.org for assistance, or you can delete specific information (or delete your or your child’s account) directly. Please note that removal of your content or information does not ensure complete or comprehensive removal, as there may be deidentified or recoverable elements of your content or information on our servers in some form. Additionally, we will not remove content or information that we may be required to retain under applicable federal and state laws. 

* * *

##  Our approach to Data Security 

###  Data security is important to you, and to us. 

To protect your privacy and security, we take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting you account access or making corrections to your information. For example, we may ask you to provide certain Personal Information to confirm your identity, and we may require that you create and use a password to access certain parts of our Properties. You should create and maintain a strong password to help ensure the security of your account. 

#####  We try to ensure that our Properties and information sent to us are safe, but no security measures are perfect. 

Khan Academy uses certain physical, managerial, and technical safeguards designed to preserve the integrity and security of your Personal Information and other information we maintain in connection with our Properties. We cannot, however, ensure or warrant the security of any or all of the information you transmit to Khan Academy, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission of information, Khan Academy makes commercially reasonable efforts to ensure the security of our systems. When you enter sensitive information, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL) or similar technologies. However, please note that this is not a guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards. 

#####  We will notify you electronically or via the Properties if Khan Academy experiences a data security incident that could affect you. 

If we learn of a data security incident that compromises or appears to compromise your Personal Information, then we will attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. We may also post a notice on our Properties if a data security incident occurs. 

* * *

##  How we maintain data integrity 

At Khan Academy, we only use Personal Information as needed for the purposes for which it was collected or where you have consented to our use of Personal Information relating to you. We take reasonable steps to ensure that the Personal Information we store and use is accurate, complete, and up-to-date. If you discover that Personal Information or other data pertaining to you is inaccurate, incomplete, or out-of-date, please update your account information or contact us as outlined below. 

* * *

##  Links to other sites 

The Properties may link to and may be linked by websites operated by other entities or individuals. Some of these websites, such as the Khan Academy Facebook page, may be co-branded with our name or logo. This Privacy Notice does not apply to, and we cannot always control the activities of, such other third-party websites. You should consult the respective privacy policies of those third-party websites. 

* * *

##  International visitors 

Our Properties are operated and managed on servers located within the United States. If you choose to use our Properties from the European Union or other regions of the world with laws governing data collection and use that differ from U.S. law, then you acknowledge and agree that you are transferring your Personal Information outside of those regions to the United States and that, by providing your Personal Information on the Properties, you consent to that transfer. 

* * *

##  Changes and updates to this Privacy Notice 

Khan Academy may modify or revise this Privacy Notice from time to time. Khan Academy will notify Users of any changes to our Privacy Notice by posting the revised Privacy Notice with an updated date of revision on our Properties, along with a short notice of the revision posted on our homepage. We will not change how we use any Personal Information in any material way without also providing notice of the change via email to you (or in the case of a Child User, to your Parent) or through the Properties, and obtaining consent to any new uses. 

* * *

##  Contacting Khan Academy 

Please contact Khan Academy with any questions or comments about this Privacy Notice, your personal information, our third-party disclosure practices, or your consent choices by email at [privacy@khanacademy.org](mailto:privacy@khanacademy.org) or by mail at: Khan Academy, PO Box 1630, Mountain View, CA 94042.
